PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Self-motivated full-stack developer with over 6 years of industry experience. I've grown from a junior developer to a management position and actively participated in all aspects of web development, from hands-on development to planning and scoping. I enjoy communicating ideas and technical concepts to clients and stakeholders in non-technical roles.

TECH STACK

Frontend

- HTML, CSS and JS
- SASS/SCSS
- Typescript
- React JS (React Query, MobX, Styled components)
- Vue JS
- MSW JS
- Webpack / Laravel Mix / Vite
- Cypress
- Imgix

Backend

- PHP (Laravel, Statamic)
- MySQL / Maria DB
- Node JS
- Linux server administration
- AWS (S3, SES, SQS, Lightsail)
- REST API design
- Shell scripting
- MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

Lead Developer, Candour

July 2021 - Present

Candour is a Norwich-based digital agency that, alongside a range of digital marketing services, has a team of designers and developers who produce bespoke full-stack web applications for clients. The company has grown from around 10 team members to 22, and during my time I have been promoted to the lead developer position. My current responsibilities at Candour include:

- Setting and maintaining internal best practices and developing processes to maintain them
- Continued role with hands-on development
- Overseeing project delivery from end to end: estimating, scoping (creation of functional specifications), design reviews, development, QA and testing, ongoing maintenance and future development
- Managing a small team of developers: recruiting, onboarding, delegating tasks and facilitating ongoing training
- Liaising with project managers, directors, designers and freelance developers on a daily basis to aid project delivery

- Daily use of Gsuite for creation of internal and external documents,
 Slack/Teams/Google Meet for communication, and ActiveCollab for project management
- Effective communication with external clients as part of project inception, planning, training and ongoing support

Web Developer, Candour

May 2018 - July 2021

- Collaborating with designers to produce pixel-perfect responsive websites using the Statamic (Laravel) CMS, WordPress and SilverStripe
- Development of bespoke addons/plugins for the CMSs we use (Aardvark SEO, Statamic Imgix, Statamic Anonymous Uploads)
- Maintaining and developing existing websites
- R&D projects leading to daily use of new technologies, for example moving existing projects to Webpack and instating CI/CD processes
- Using version control (Git) in a collaborative team environment
- Frontend React JS build for our SaaS product (https://alsoasked.com)

Web Developer and Designer, Bigfork

August 2016 - May 2018

Bigfork is a Norwich-based web design and development agency specialising in B2B websites. In my role, I helped deliver websites for a wide variety of clients, working on projects of different sizes across the public and private sectors.

- Producing website designs from client briefs
- Developing websites using the SilverStripe PHP framework
- Self-led training on producing CMS websites from a brief

PORTFOLIO OF PROJECTS

Aardvark SEO (Candour)

https://statamic.com/addons/candour/aardvark-seo

Since 2019 I've led the development for a Statamic addon which provides many features to enhance the SEO capabilities of sites built using the CMS. The addon has achieved popularity within the community and is currently a "featured addon" on the marketplace.

- Use of core Laravel functionality (middleware, event listeners/subscribers and custom routes, views and controllers)
- Extending Statamic's functionality to build custom template tags and CMS fieldtypes (Vue JS)
- Knowledge of best SEO practices to:
 - o Generate automatic XML sitemaps (and provide styles with XSLT)
 - \circ Generate automatic schema snippets
 - Add hreflang tags for multi-lingual sites
 - Add automated open graph/social sharing tags

How Many Spaces? - Norwich (Personal)

December 2022 - Present

https://norwich.howmanyspaces.com

This is the MVP for my most recent project. The app displays the current number of available spaces for the various car parks around Norwich in a user-friendly and accessible format. The backend is built in Laravel, using queued jobs to import the data every 5 minutes and Laravel Nova for an admin interface.

The frontend uses the NextJS framework, React Query, and Typescript and I have focussed on strict typing over the stack which has helped to reduce bugs and improve the maintainability of the project going forward.

I was responsible for all aspects of this project:

- UI and UX design
- REST API design
- Frontend development
- Backend development
- Use of MSW JS for API mocking to aid frontend prototyping and testing
- Setting up deployment pipeline (via Deployer/Vercel)
- Provisioning and maintaining a Linux server to host the laravel app

Radio Roulette (Personal)

April 2020 - Present

https://radioroulette.uk

Starting out as an idea to keep office-based radio listening choices fresh, Radio Roulette is a small project I built on the side which will select a random radio station from a list of ~160 and provide information on how to tune in. The app uses React JS and HTML canvas, Koa (A Node JS framework) and MongoDB. I also carried out the UI and logo design for this project.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

ILM (Leadership and Management) Level 3, Jarrold Training

October 2021 - February 2022

Team leadership, decision-making, effective delegation, time management, understanding and adapting communication styles using the <u>Insights Discovery</u> model.





Epicreact.dev, Online

December 2021

EDUCATION

Attleborough High School & Sixth Form

2009 - 2016

Completed GCSEs, achieving 14 A*-C grades (including English, Maths, IT and Science) and A-levels in Maths, Chemistry and Music.